(
"ai_sub_version": "1.9.1",
"subtitles_prompt_version": 2,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": "gemini-cli:gemini-3-flash-preview",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true
),
"gemini_cli": (
"timeout": 600
)
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": true,
"fps": 1,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"encoder": "libx264"
)
),
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 1,
"subtitles": 2
),
"retry": (
"run": 3,
"max": 9,
"delay": 30
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": false,
"scrub": true
)
開演までしばらくお待ちください。
Please wait a moment until the performance begins.
はっ、光った流れ星 願いそびれ もう一回を待った
あっという間に夜が明け もういいや このまんま散歩しよう
Ha, a shooting star flashed, I missed my chance to wish and waited for another one
In the blink of an eye, the night has dawned, forget it, I'll just go for a walk like this
はっ、横切った野良猫 色は黒 でも可愛いから優勝
パン屋さんが開くのは七時 あと十分 何しようかな
Ha, a stray cat crossed my path, it was black but cute so it wins
The bakery opens at seven, ten more minutes, what should I do?
どまり、もしもしカメさんよ 今だけは君になりたい
ぴょんと跳んだウサギさん ひょんなこと 雹が降る 豹に出会う
Wait, hello Mr. Turtle, for now I want to be you
A rabbit hopped by, and out of nowhere, hail falls and I meet a leopard
冬にだけ可視化される声の温度が
春や夏や秋はどこへと 消えてしまうのか
The temperature of the voice that is only visualized in winter...
Where does it go in spring, summer, or autumn? Does it just disappear?
きっとそこにある 触れる 揺らぐ
気づいて 気づいてって まるで心の中みたい
It's surely there, touching, swaying
'Notice it, notice it,' it's just like the inside of a heart
冬にだけ可視化される声の温度が
春や夏や秋は誰かに 届いてるのかな だってここにない 消える 消える
Does the temperature of the voice only visualized in winter
Reach someone in spring, summer, or autumn? Because it's not here, it disappears, disappears
暑さも寒さも全部 ちょうどいいの前触れ
The heat, the cold, it's all just a prelude to 'just right'
急速! 追加公演決定!
Express! Additional performance decided!
わっ、瞬間、風が吹いた どこかのお家が儲かったのだろう
彼女が大事にしたのは 直球級のラブレター
Wa! In an instant, the wind blew, some house probably made a profit
What she cherished was a straight-up love letter
空を待って 伝って 僕が拾う そんな運命道を途中下車
僕が 僕の呼吸を重ねる
Waiting for the sky, tracing it, I'll pick it up, getting off that fated path halfway
I overlap my breathing
長い長い旅 ゆっくりと進んでいこう
何でも解決してくれる 時間てやつが相棒だから 息を吸って
A long, long journey, let's move forward slowly
Time, the guy who solves everything, is my partner, so take a breath
長い長い旅 お腹減った そろそろ
A long, long journey, I'm hungry, it's about time
焼きたてのパンの香りに思わず カメもウサギになる
街灯もまたたいて眠った 入れ替わり目を覚ました
The smell of freshly baked bread makes me instinctively turn from a turtle into a rabbit
The streetlights also flickered and slept, waking up in turn
おいしそ
Looks delicious
青くて澄んだ空を ぎゅっと抱きしめて 今日も最高だ
Holding the blue and clear sky tight, today is also the best
知らないわけ きっと 怖くて 分かるわけ きっと 安心できる
The reason I don't know, surely I'm scared, the reason I understand, surely I can feel safe
でも私が選ぶのは ありえないの向こう側
But what I choose is the side of the impossible
青くて澄んだ空を 胸いっぱい吸い込んで
Taking a deep breath of the blue and clear sky
透明になるまで 声を鳴らせ
Let your voice ring out until you become transparent
私が誰かを照らせ まだ 誰かの救いになったら
May I shine on someone, if I can still become someone's salvation
奇跡のひとつでも 起こせるような気がするよ 歌声は溶けて朝になる
I feel like I can make even one miracle happen, my singing voice melts and becomes morning
悲しみごと抱いて 微熱を帯びる
Embracing all the sadness, it carries a slight fever
そうだ この気持ちに 名前をつけるなら
That's right, if I were to give this feeling a name
手を見せ合って行こうぜ
Let's show our hands to each other
青くて旬な夢を 胸いっぱい仕舞い込んで
Tucking away fresh, blue dreams in our hearts
溢れたその分だけ
Just as much as overflowed
思い出そうぜ
Let's remember
私が正しい幸せだったら
If I were the right kind of happiness
悔やむことさえなかったら
If there were no regrets
心に眠った衝動に 気付くこともないから
I wouldn't have noticed the impulses sleeping in my heart
歌声は涙に寄り添う
My singing voice nestles close to tears
ときめきごと抱いて
Embracing every heartbeat
微熱を帯びる そうだ
It carries a fever, that's right
この気持ちに名前を付けるなら
If I were to give this feeling a name
花が咲けば枯れていく
When flowers bloom, they wither away
種を蒔けば宿っていく
When seeds are sown, they take root
運命に意味なんて 元からなくていいんじゃない
Destiny doesn't need to have meaning from the start
咲き誇れ 地 笑え
Bloom in full glory, earth, smile
私が誰かを照らせるなら
If I can shine a light on someone
誰かの救いになったら
If I become someone's salvation
奇跡の一つでも 起こせるような気がするよ
I feel like I could even cause a miracle
歌声は溶けて朝になる
My singing voice melts and becomes the morning
悲しみごと抱いて
Embracing all the sadness
微熱を帯びる 空が
It carries a fever, the sky is
暖かくて綺麗だ 私はなんだか
so warm and beautiful, I feel somehow
小粋な
Smart
この気持ちが 愛しくて大好きだったんだ
I loved this feeling so much, it was precious to me
名前のないこの気持ちを
This nameless feeling
改正 修正 反映 構成 マエストラテジー
Revision, correction, reflection, composition, my strategy
のんびりと ゆったりと まったりと ほっこりも
Leisurely, relaxedly, calmly, warmly,
いいんだけど いつもそんなんじゃないないね
it's nice, but it's not always like that
ちょっとだけ冒険もしなくちゃ
I've got to go on a bit of an adventure, too
気合入れて そっと携帯のメモ帳に書いた
Gathering my strength, I quietly wrote it in my phone's notepad
浮き足立っちゃって クラクラり
Getting all flustered, my head's spinning
なんてなったら とりまうたいます
If that happens, I'll just sing for now
妄想 爆上がり ふわふわり
Delusions soaring, floating lightly
ドキドキが止まらない 22時
My heart won't stop pounding, 10 PM
あっちこっち どっちがいいのかな
Here and there, which one is better?
君ともっと一緒に行けるかな
I wonder if I can go further with you
シチュエーション 混濁で どっちのち
Situation confused, which way after?
これこそが高度な情報戦
This is exactly a high-level information war
完全 安全 最善 万全 飲んで 噛んで 速攻対応
Complete, safe, best, thorough—drink, chew, immediate response
改正 修正 反映 構成 マエストラテジー ツギ！
Revision, correction, reflection, composition, my strategy. NEXT!
反省の対象は 習慣生活の怠惰 知って
The target of reflection is the laziness of daily habits. Knowing that
抜本の改正は 万全や 市場挟まずに
Fundamental revision is perfect, without hesitation
万全の体制は 冷静な 理性に反して
A perfect system goes against calm reason
想定外展開に ねねとねねが 渋滞中
In an unexpected development, Nene and Nene are in a traffic jam
完璧なフェイントで クラクラり
With a perfect feint, my head's spinning
なんでもっと早く言ってくれないかな
Why didn't you tell me sooner?
こんなんじゃダメでも 味気曖昧に
Even if this is no good, flavorless and ambiguous
気付けば加速 ことの24時
Before I know it, things accelerate at midnight
あっちこっち どっちがいいのかな
Here and there, which one is better?
32分音符で 黒々シャッフル
Shuffling darkly in 32nd notes
ラグがもどかしい どっちのち
The lag is frustrating, which way after?
これこそが高度な情報戦
This is exactly a high-level information war
教えてよ 有識者
Tell me, experts!
ここはどこ 私は誰だっけ
Where is this? Who am I again?
彩りどり よりどりみどり 選択肢はたくさんあるけど
Colorful, take your pick—there are many options, but...
悩んでる時間がもー無理 開店ダッシュ ラストオーダー
I can't stand the time spent worrying anymore. Opening dash, last order!
ハイになっちゃって お得になっちゃって 消費する
Getting high, getting a good deal, I consume
速度が
The speed
息急いで走った分だけ
Just as much as I ran out of breath
寿命だって早く来ちゃったりして
My life might even come to an end sooner
息切れして声も出ないの
Out of breath, I can't even speak
タイムパフォーマンス コスパパフォーマンス
Time performance, cost performance
言葉 踊り狂う僕らって万能ね
Words, we're all-powerful as we dance wildly
毎日焼かれてやり直しよ
Every day we're burned and start over
ランチタイムくらい まったりさせて
At least let me relax during lunchtime
Wow wow wow wow... 跡も欲しくない
Wow wow wow wow... I don't even want a trace
Wow wow wow wow... さあさ掘り込め
Wow wow wow wow... Come on, dig in
Wow wow wow wow... 口の中が溶けてゆく
Wow wow wow wow... My mouth is melting
あれここはどこ 私は誰だっけ
Wait, where is this? Who was I again?
拝啓 石の上にも三年もいられない者たち
To those who can't stay on a stone for three years
任せたっていい やめたっていい
It's okay to leave it, it's okay to quit
量販店還元大バーゲン
Mass retailer return giant bargain
的外れでオートだね
Missing the mark, it's automatic
感情の足音ペース
The pace of emotion's footsteps
頑張るって無駄なベース
Doing your best is a useless base
半信半疑 四季折々 風情もりもり
Half-convinced, season by season, full of elegance
流れるのを緩やかに愛でて
Gently appreciate what flows
味わって急がば回れ
Taste it, and make haste slowly
知ってるはずが焦り耳を凝らして
I should know, but in my impatience, I strain my ears
どうになっちゃって あららになっちゃって
What's happened, oh my
ママを忘る心が
The heart that forgets its mother
削ぎ落として絞った分だけ
Just as much as I've shaved off and squeezed out
痩せ細って弱くなっちゃったりして
I might even become thin and weak
息を吸って声を出して
Take a breath and speak up
あれもしたい これもしたい そんな欲望抱くだけで死ぬ人生
I want to do that, I want to do this, a life that ends just harboring such desires
I'm sorry 開いて大人になっちゃって
I'm sorry, opening up and becoming an adult
腹八分目なんて真っ平ら 真っ平ら ごめんなさい
Being eighty percent full is absolutely flat, I'm sorry
タイムパフォーマンス コスパパフォーマンス
Time performance, cost performance
言葉 踊り狂う僕らって万能ね
Words, we're all-powerful as we dance wildly
毎日焼かれてやり直しよ
Every day we're burned and start over
ランチタイムくらい まったりさせて
At least let me relax during lunchtime
Wow wow wow wow... 跡も欲しくない
Wow wow wow wow... I don't even want a trace
Wow wow wow wow... さあさ掘り込め
Wow wow wow wow... Come on, dig in
Wow wow wow wow... 口の中が溶けてゆく
Wow wow wow wow... My mouth is melting
あれここはどこ 私は誰だっけ
Wait, where is this? Who was I again?
捕まえた
I caught you
でも逃げた
But you ran away
繰り返す本能には
In the repeating instinct
諦める
I give up
術はない
There is no way
無理にさえも手を伸ばすだけ
I only reach out even if it's impossible
だから強く
So, strongly
見つめ合えば
If we gaze at each other
今を生き抜く石屑
Stone fragments to survive the present
描き添えて
Draw and add to it
色のない未来を裂けた
Tearing through the colorless future
今は分岐は無限でも
Even if the branches are infinite now
君と交差したい時の果て
The end of time where I want to cross paths with you
期待値が高すぎたって
Even if expectations were too high
そこに追いついて鋭い感情を指した
I catch up there and point out sharp emotions
今は詰まりは何だって
Now, what is the blockage?
嘘は負ける星が合致してしまう
Lies lose, the stars end up matching
綺麗な偽りを見抜いて
See through the beautiful lies
心のまま Chaotic world
As your heart desires, Chaotic world
紐解いた
I unraveled it
また増えた
It increased again
名残惜しくない運命なら
If it's a fate I don't miss
振り返る
I look back
暇はない
There is no time
闇よりも早い選択
Choices faster than darkness
誰を満たす
Who to satisfy
誰かよりも
More than anyone
まずは胸の中凝視
First, gaze into your chest
狂い合いに
In the mutual madness
星はただ輝きをまっすぐに届ける
The stars just deliver their brilliance straight ahead
今は全部は知らないけど
I don't know everything now, but
君と共有した甘い鼓動
The sweet heartbeat I shared with you
揺らいでる天体の前で
Before the wavering celestial bodies
消えないように灯火をさえ 重い重いけど
So they don't go out, even the lanterns are heavy
今はいつの間にかでも
Even if it's sometime now
嘘に染まるなんて無理だから
Because it's impossible to be stained by lies
正論と笑われる まだ誇りになら Chaotic world
Laughed at as the correct argument, still pride, Chaotic world
急遽！追加公演決定！
Sudden! Additional performance decided!
さなぎだって これなら遠くへ
Even a chrysalis, with this, can go far
さなぎだって
Even a chrysalis
信じて 信じて 信じたくて
Believe, believe, I want to believe
歌を教え合って 出来るなら 絶対
Teaching each other songs, if we can, absolutely
壊れても 壊れても 静かに小さな欠片が
Even if it breaks, even if it breaks, quiet small fragments
蘇る 音 こんなに大事に感じるのは きっと 君との絆だからね
The sound revives; the reason it feels so precious is surely because of my bond with you
今夜は 分岐は無限でも 君と交差した時の果て
Tonight, even if the branches are infinite, the end of time when I crossed paths with you
期待値が高すぎたって そこに追いついて
Even if expectations were too high, catching up to them
鋭利な感謝を差し出す夢を
A dream of offering sharp gratitude
今夜は 不純なのだって 嘘は負ける
Tonight, even if it's impure, lies will lose
星が指してしまう 綺麗な世界で生きていた
The stars point to it; I lived in a beautiful world
偽りも見抜いて心のまま Cut in
See through the lies and just as your heart desires, cut in
あー 一言みたいな夜だ
Ah, it's a night like a single word
ばらまいた星だけが キラリ澄んでいる
Only the scattered stars are sparkling and clear
そんなに綺麗にはなれないや それでも今夜行くための歌
I can't become that beautiful, but still, a song to move through tonight
あー ほんの小さな夜だ 寝るには早く
Ah, it's a tiny night, too early to sleep
夜明けはまだ遠く 憧れるには遅く 挫けるにはまだ早いよ
Dawn is still far, too late to yearn, too early to give up
言葉は いつまでも下手だよ
Words are always clumsy
ため息だけが 上手になるよ
Only sighing becomes skillful
傷つくたび 違う生き物だと知るの
Every time I'm hurt, I learn that we are different creatures
いつだって暗闇で迷子
Always a lost child in the darkness
開けない 夜があったなら
If there was a night that wouldn't end
このまま 溶けて 消えたいな
I'd want to just melt and disappear like this
開けない 夜があったって
Even if there's a night that wouldn't end
私は 煌めく星に なれなくていい
I don't need to become a sparkling star
煌めく星に なれなくていい
あー 本日の閉店です
Ah, we are closed for today
どうにかこうにか 1日
Somehow, another day
ひっそりこっそり よく頑張り 何かは残せたのでしょうか
Quietly, secretly, doing my best; was I able to leave something behind?
希望的だ
It's hopeful
刹那的だ
It's ephemeral
楽観的だ
It's optimistic
でも きっと 眩しいよ
But surely, it's dazzling
言葉は いつまでも下手だよ
Words are always clumsy
ため息だけが 上手になるよ
Only sighing becomes skillful
傷ついて 違う生き物だと知って
Being hurt and knowing we are different creatures
それでも 精一杯 歌うよ
Even so, I will sing with all my might
泣きたい 夜があったなら
If there was a night I wanted to cry
笑えない 夜があったなら
If there was a night I couldn't laugh
溶けて 消えて なくなって
Melt away, disappear, and be gone
きっと もう一度 ゼロから 始めよう
Surely, let's start over once more from zero
明日のことは 分からないや
I don't know about tomorrow
昨日のことは 知らないや
I don't know about yesterday
開けない 夜があったって
Even if there's a night that wouldn't end
私は 煌めく星に なれなくていい
I don't need to become a sparkling star
煌めく星に なれなくていい
そんな今夜 素敵に 生きるための歌
On such a night, a song to live wonderfully
AZKi メジャー 1st アルバム「Route If」配信中！
AZKi Major 1st Album "Route If" Now Available!
2024.7.24 リリース メジャー 1st アルバム「Route If」収録曲リスト
2024.7.24 Release Major 1st Album "Route If" Tracklist
初回限定盤 特典 DISC 2 アコースティックアレンジ収録曲
First Press Limited Edition Bonus DISC 2 Acoustic Arrange Tracks
窓の向こう　星たちを
Beyond the window, the stars
数えてたら　眠ってた
As I was counting them, I fell asleep
その寝息と　いつか混ざる
With that breathing, someday I'll mix in
画面の向こう　そばにいる
Beyond the screen, I'm by your side
言葉なんてない　傷つくこともない
There are no words, no getting hurt
まるでね　エトランゼ　愛しくて
Just like an etranger, so dear
こんなにそばにいるのに　本当は遠い存在
Even though I'm this close, you're actually a distant presence
使えてた言葉が　涙になったフレーバー
The words I used to use have turned into tears, a flavor
今日も頑張ったんだね
You did your best today too
本当は手を差し伸べたい
I really want to reach out a hand
ああ　私の知らない
Ah, about you
君のことを
whom I don't know
どうすればいい？　何でもない
What should I do? It's nothing
何かすると　崩れそう
If I do something, it feels like it'll crumble
独りここで　思いを馳せ
Alone here, letting my thoughts wander
時間だけが　過ぎてゆく
Only time passes by
知らないうち
Before I knew it
星は広がってた
the stars had spread out
君だけ　君だけを待ってる
I'm waiting for only you, only you
パノラマ
Panorama
雲の向こう
Beyond the clouds
ゆらゆらと
Swaying gently
イメージは
The image
心地いいのに
Even though it's comfortable
こんなにそばにいるのに　本当は遠い存在
Even though I'm this close, you're actually a distant presence
会いたいな　会えないな
I want to see you, I can't see you
吸い込まれた気持ち
these feelings were sucked in
今日も頑張ったんだね
You did your best today too
どうか君に届くように
I hope it reaches you somehow
ああ　見守ってる
Ah, I'm watching over you
ずっと遠くから
from far away
急遽！追加公演決定！
Urgent! Additional performance decided!
たとえばなら それはドレスのように
For example, if it were like a dress
すっかり装いを変えて
Changing its appearance completely
優しい光で輝き出す
Starting to shine with a gentle light
夜の街
The night city
眠れないなら 暗闇はいっそ
If you can't sleep, the darkness might as well
差し入れを贈ってくださった開拓者の皆様、本当にありがとうございます！
To all the Pioneers who sent gifts, thank you very much!
全部宇宙だと思えば
Be thought of as the whole universe
ずっと近くに居るより不思議と
Strangely, rather than being close forever
怖くないよ
It's not scary
話すことを 本当はいくつもあったけど
In truth, there were many things to talk about, but
言葉より 想い溢れ出して
Emotions overflow more than words
響けよシンフォニー
Resonate, symphony
感じ合えたメロディー
The melody we felt together
AZKi メジャー1stアルバム Route If 配信中！
AZKi Major 1st Album Route If is now available!
そっと言葉も常識もいらないでしょう
Gently, neither words nor common sense are needed, right?
君と歌えるのなら
If I can sing with you
見渡せばほらこの夜に
Look around, in this night
おおおおー！
Oooooh!
10!
9!
8!
7!
6!
5!
4!
3!
2!
1!
AZKi Major Debut LiVE 『声音エントロピー』
AZKi Major Debut LiVE "Kowane Entropy"
あ、光った流れ星
Oh, a shooting star flashed by.
願いそびれもう一回を待った
I missed my chance to wish and waited for another.
あっという間に夜が明け
In the blink of an eye, dawn broke,
もういいやこのまんま散歩しよう
well, I'll just go for a walk like this.
あ、横切った野良猫
Oh, a stray cat crossed my path.
色は黒 でも可愛いから優勝
It's black, but since it's cute, it's a winner.
パン屋さんが開くのは七時
The bakery opens at seven.
あと十分 何しようかな
Ten more minutes... what should I do?
隣、もしもし亀さんよ
Next door, hello Mr. Turtle.
今だけは君になりたい
For now, I want to be like you.
ぴょんと飛んだうさぎさん
Mr. Rabbit who jumped away,
ひょんなこと 豹が降る 雹に出会う
unexpectedly, a leopard falls, meeting the hail.
理屈だって合ってないようなもんで
Logic doesn't really seem to apply anyway,
ファンタジー浮かべ今日もニヒル
imagining a fantasy, nihilistic again today.
そこの街灯すらも意外と
Even that streetlight, surprisingly,
僕がイヤホン外したら歌い出す
starts singing if I take off my earphones.
Na na na...
冬にだけ可視化される声の温度が
The temperature of the voice, visible only in winter,
春や夏や秋はどこへと消えてしまうのか
where does it disappear to in spring, summer, or autumn?
きっとそこにある
Surely, it's right there.
触れる 揺らぐ
Touching, swaying.
気づいて 気づいてって まるで心の中みたい
"Notice me, notice me," just like the inside of my heart.
冬にだけ可視化される声の温度が
The temperature of the voice, visible only in winter,
春や夏や秋は誰かに届いてるのかな
is it reaching someone in spring, summer, or autumn?
だってここにない
Because it's not here.
消える 消える
Vanishing, vanishing.
暑さも 寒さも 全部ちょうどいいの前触れ
The heat, the cold, all just a prelude to being just right.
わっ 瞬間風が吹いた
Whoosh! A gust of wind blew for a second.
どこかの桶屋が儲かったのだろう
I guess some tub-maker made a profit somewhere.
彼女が大事に温めた
The extra-large love letter
特大級のラブレター
that she cherished and kept warm,
空を待って 伝って 僕が拾う
waiting in the sky, traveling along, I'll pick it up.
そんな運命待ちお途中下車
Waiting for such a fate, getting off halfway,
僕は僕の呼吸を重ねる
I layer my breath with my own.
長い長い旅 ゆっくりと進んでいこう
A long, long journey... let's move forward slowly.
なんでも解決してくれる時間ってやつが相棒だから
Because Time, who solves everything, is my partner.
息を吸って
Take a breath.
長い長い旅
A long, long journey.
お腹減った そろそろ
I'm hungry... it's about time.
焼きたてのパンの香りに思わず
At the smell of freshly baked bread, instinctively,
亀もうさぎに乗る
even the turtle rides on the rabbit.
街灯も瞬いて眠った
The streetlights flickered and went to sleep.
入れ替わり目を覚ました
In their place, waking up,
通り達 もしもし もしもし
the streets... hello, hello.
ドキドキは奇跡 もしもし
This excitement is a miracle... hello.
始まり始まり おしかし
It's starting, it's starting... but wait.
始めよう、この夜
Let's begin this night.
いくよ、開拓者！
Here we go, Pioneers!
あの日選んで決めた道は
The path I chose and decided on that day,
間違いだったんだろって過去恨んでみても
even if I resent the past, thinking it was a mistake,
土砂降りの雨責め立てて
the pouring rain reproaches me,
うつむいた顔は酷く
and my downcast face looks terrible.
...ありふれた日々に気づいた
...I noticed it in these ordinary days.
この先には
Ahead of us,
叶えたいことや夢があるから
there are things I want to achieve and dreams to fulfill.
目を逸らさないように
So that I won't look away.
正解はない
There is no correct answer.
誰だって一人で
Anyone, by themselves,
思うまま始まっていく
starts it just as they want to.
この物語
This story...
今はただ走って
For now, just run,
季節を駆け巡って
running through the seasons,
見えない暗闇の中で
within the invisible darkness.
痛みだってあるよ
There is pain too.
戸惑いだってあるよ
There is confusion too.
それでもここで生きていくと
But still, to live here is what I've...
決めたんだ
...decided.
決めたから
Because I've decided,
前を向いて
I'll look forward.
生き方を誰かに決められて
With my way of life decided by someone else,
本当はそうじゃなかったとか
saying things like it wasn't supposed to be this way...
今さら嘆いたって
even if I lament it now.
右も左も現れなくて
Neither right nor left appeared,
喧騒の中で
and in the midst of the bustle,
どこか彷徨い果てていた
I was wandering aimlessly somewhere.
この先には
Ahead of us,
奏でたいことや歌があるから
there are things I want to play and songs to sing.
耳を研ぎ澄ますように
As if sharpening my hearing.
間違いはない
There is no mistake.
誰だって一人で
Anyone, by themselves,
綴り綴られていく
spells it out and gets spelled out.
この物語
This story...
過去今未来が
Past, present, and future
あなたを駆け巡って
run through you.
理想と現実の中で
Between ideal and reality,
泣きたくもなるよ
I feel like crying sometimes.
諦めたくもなるよ
I feel like giving up sometimes.
それでもここで生きていくと
But still, to live here is what I've...
決めたんだ
...decided.
決めたから
Because I've decided,
走り出すよ
I'll start running.
生まれ変わっても
Even if I'm reborn,
この話をしよう
let's tell this story.
この人生でよかったと
Saying that I'm glad to have lived this life.
痛みは力に
Turning pain into strength,
戸惑いは期待に
turning confusion into expectation.
そうしてここで生きていくと
And so, to live here is what I've...
決めたんだ
...decided.
今はただ走って
For now, just run,
季節を駆け巡って
running through the seasons,
見えない暗闇の中で
within the invisible darkness.
痛みだってあるよ
There is pain too.
戸惑いだってあるよ
There is confusion too.
それでもここで生きていくと
But still, to live here is what I've...
決めたんだ
...decided.
決めたから
Because I've decided,
前を向いて
I'll look forward.
ああ　一言みたいな夜だ　ばら撒いた星だけがキラリ澄んでいる
Ah, it's a night like a single word. Only the scattered stars are sparkling and clear.
そんなに綺麗にはなれないな　それでも今夜行くための歌
I can't be that beautiful. Still, this is a song to move forward tonight.
みんなー！夜公演も盛り上がっていくぞー！横浜ーー！
Everyone! Let's get fired up for the evening performance! Yokohama--!
ああ　ほんの小さな夜だ　寝るには早く夜明けはまだ遠く
Ah, it's just a small night. Too early to sleep, and the dawn is still far away.
憧れるには遅く　くじけるにはまだ早い夜
A night too late to yearn, yet too early to give up.
言葉はいつまでも下手だよ
My words are always clumsy.
ため息だけが上手になるよ
Only my sighs become skillful.
傷つくたび違う生き物だと知るよ
Every time I'm hurt, I learn we're different creatures.
いつだって暗闇で迷子
I'm always a lost child in the darkness.
明けない夜があったなら
If there were a night that never ended,
このまま溶けて消えたいな
I'd want to just melt and disappear like this.
明けない夜があったって
Even if there's a night that never ends
私は煌めく星になれなくていい
I don't need to become a twinkling star
煌めく星になれなくていい
あ、本日も閉店です
Ah, we're closed for today as well
どうにかこうにか一日
Somehow managing through the day
ひっそりこっそりよく頑張り
Working hard quietly and secretly
何かを残せたのでしょうか
Did I manage to leave something behind?
希望的だ
It's hopeful
刹那的だ
It's ephemeral
楽観的だ
It's optimistic
でも きっと美しいよ
But it's surely beautiful
美しいよ 美しいよ
It's beautiful, it's beautiful
言葉はいつまでも下手だよ
Words will always be clumsy
溜息だけが上手になるよ
I'm only good at sighing
傷付いて違う生き物だとして
Even if we're different beings that get hurt
それでも精一杯歌うよ
I'll still sing with all my might
泣きたい夜があったなら
If there were nights you wanted to cry
笑えない夜があったなら
If there were nights you couldn't smile
溶けて消えてなくなって
Melt away and disappear
きっともう一度ゼロから始めよう
And surely let's start from zero once again
明日のことはわからないや
I don't know about tomorrow
昨日のことはしないで
Don't dwell on yesterday
明けない夜があったって
Even if there's a night that never ends
私は煌めく星になれなくていい
I don't need to become a twinkling star
煌めく星になれなくていい
そんな声や素敵に生きるための歌
Those voices and a song for living beautifully
ありがとう！
Thank you!
こんこんこんこあずきー！
Kon-kon-kon-kozuki!
右手にマイク、
Mic in my right hand,
左手に地図、
map in my left,
あなたのハートにゼロゲッサー！
zero-guess into your heart!
AZKiです！
I'm AZKi!
始まりました夜公演、
The evening performance has begun,
みんな来てくれてありがとう！
thank you everyone for coming!
はい、本日は、えー、昼と夜ということで、
Yes, today, as we have both day and evening sessions,
AZKi Major Debut LiVE「声音エントロピー」お越しいただき
thank you for coming to AZKi's Major Debut Live "Kowairo Entropy"!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you very much!
うわー、めちゃめちゃペンライトが綺麗です。
Wow, the penlights are so beautiful.
はい、今日はですね、生バンドを迎えて、
Yes, today, with a live band,
声と音とみんなの思いで
I want to make this a concert where we become one through
一体感のあるライブにしたいなと思っております。
voices, sounds, and everyone's feelings.
会場のみんなも、配信のみんなも、
Everyone at the venue and everyone watching the stream,
ぜひペンライトを持って、
please hold your penlights
一緒に盛り上がってください！
and let's get excited together!
そしてそして、今日はKT Zepp Yokohamaということで、
And also, as we are at KT Zepp Yokohama today,
みんなでゲスしたいです。
I want to "guess" with everyone.
いくよ！
Here we go!
KT Zepp Yokohamaに、
To KT Zepp Yokohama,
ゲス！ありがとう！
Guess! Thank you!
みんな来てくれてありがとう！道迷わなかった？
Thank you all for coming! Did you get lost on the way?
道迷ってない？大丈夫？ちゃんと下車できたもんね。
You didn't get lost? Are you okay? You got off at the right station, right?
ここにいるみんなはちゃんと下車できたもんね。
Everyone here was able to get off correctly.
ありがとうございます。はい、そしてすでにお伝えしておりますが、
Thank you very much. Yes, and as I've already mentioned,
昼と夜でセットリストが全然違うんです！
the setlist for the afternoon and evening shows is completely different!
はい、ということでね、早速3曲とも、
Yes, so, right away, all three songs—
あ、レイジーは一緒だったけど、その後のね、
well, 'Lazy' was the same, but the setlist after that
セットリストも変わっておりますので、ぜひぜひぜひぜひ最後まで楽しんでいってほしいと思います！
has changed, so I really hope you enjoy it until the very end!
よろしく！
Thank you!
はい、そしてSNS、えーハッシュタグ
Yes, and for SNS, the hashtag is
#AZKiワンマン横浜夜 でぜひ盛り上げてください！
#AZKiワンマン横浜夜, so please post and get things excited!
配信のみんな、頼んだ！よろしく！
Everyone on the stream, I'm counting on you! Thanks!
会場のみんなもね、終わったらいっぱい、いっぱい、いっぱいポストしてください。お願いします。
Everyone at the venue too, please post a lot, a lot, a lot after it's over. Please.
ということで、今日はね、先週リリースいたしました「Route If」も引っ提げて今日のライブやっていこうと思っております。
So, today, I'm performing this live featuring 'Route If,' which was released last week.
そう、ちょっと昼で触れられなかったんですけど、今日のステージめちゃくちゃ素敵じゃないですか？
Right, I didn't get a chance to mention it during the afternoon show, but isn't today's stage design just wonderful?
このね、このね、そうAZKiのこの音楽とか歌とか音とかのモチーフを、このね五線譜、
This, you see, they've created this stage by incorporating motifs from AZKi's music, songs, and sounds into things like the musical staff,
ね、この音符とかにこう込めてステージを作ってくださいました。
and notes.
素晴らしい！嬉しい！ありがとう！
It's wonderful! I'm so happy! Thank you!
ということで、ここで残念なお知らせです。
So, I have some unfortunate news at this point.
YouTubeで見てる無料配信はここまでになります！
The free stream on YouTube ends here!
なんでー！もっと見たいよね！もっと見たい！もっと見たい！
Why?! You want to see more, right?! More! More!
そんなあなたは、この先、配信チケットをゲットしてお楽しみください！
If you want to see more, please get a streaming ticket and enjoy the rest!
ね、みんなの声も聞こえるし、えーぜひぜひ最後まで見ていってほしいと思います。
Right, I can hear everyone's voices, so I really want you to watch until the end.
昼と全然違うステージになると思うのでよろしくお願いします。
I think it'll be a completely different performance from the afternoon, so please look forward to it.
国内向けはSPWNにて、海外向けはStreaming+さんにて配信チケット発売中です。よろしくお願いします。
Streaming tickets are now on sale at SPWN for domestic viewers and Streaming+ for overseas viewers. Thank you.
はい、みんなありがとう！ということで、こっから盛り上がっていきたいと思います。みんな盛り上がる準備できてる！？
Yes, thank you everyone! So, let's get even more excited from here. Everyone, are you ready to get fired up?!
できてる！？
Are you ready?!
本当に本当に盛り上がれますか！？
Can you really, really get fired up?!
ありがとう！最後まで楽しんで盛り上がっていきましょう！
Thank you! Let's enjoy ourselves and get excited until the very end!
捕まえた でも逃げた
I caught it, but it escaped
繰り返す 本能には
Within the repeating instincts
諦める 術はない
There's no way to give up
無味さえも 手放す
I let go of even the tastelessness
だけ
only
本当に大切なもの握りしめて
Holding on to what's truly important
純粋な正体でいたいだけ
I just want to remain as my pure self
だから強く見つめ合えば
So if we look intensely at each other
今を生き抜く設計図
It's the blueprint for surviving the present
エントロピー 色のない
Entropy, avoiding a
未来を避けて 限界はわかんないよ
colorless future, I don't know the limits
銀河の分岐は無限でも
Even if the branches of the galaxy are infinite
君と交差して
I cross paths with you
冒頭無料はこちらで終了です。
The free preview ends here.
本編続きをご視聴されたい方は、SPWNにてご購入お願いします。
If you wish to watch the rest of the main performance, please purchase on SPWN.
冒頭無料はこちらで終了です。
本編続きをご視聴されたい方は、SPWNにてご購入お願いします。
The free preview ends here.
Please purchase the full show on SPWN to continue watching.
冒頭無料はこちらで終了です。
The free introductory portion ends here.
本編続きをご視聴されたい方は、SPWNにてご購入お願いします。
If you wish to continue watching the main part, please purchase it on SPWN.
冒頭無料はこちらで終了です。
本編続きをご視聴されたい方は、SPWNにてご購入お願いします。
The free preview ends here.
To watch the rest, please purchase it on SPWN.